Finding Aid for the Nat Farber Television Show Music Arrangements PASC-M.0033
UCLA Library Special Collections
Nat Farber television show music arrangements
1955-1975
UCLA Library Special Collections
Farber, Nat
PASC-M.0033
6.6 Linear Feet (4 flat boxes and 5 oversize flat boxes)
The collection consists of manuscript scores for arrangements by Nat Farber and others for The Carol Burnett Show, The Danny Kaye Show, The Dinah Shore Chevy Show, and other productions. Also included are scripts and rehearsal schedules for The Carol Burnett Show.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift, 27 September 1975.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9912986543606533
We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.
Biography
Nat Farber (born 20 January 1918) was an American composer, pianist and arranger, who worked for several television programs and for the film studios of RKO, Columbia, and Disney. Born in Chicago, IL, Farber attended the Chicago Musical College and later the Los Angeles Conservatory of Music. He studied with Ernst Toch and Mario Castelnuovo- Tedesco. Notable work includes the Dina Shore Show (1959-1963), the Danny Kaye Show (1963- 1967), and the Carol Burnett Show (1967- 1975). He also worked in the music department for the Roy Rogers Show (1951), The Andy Williams Show (1959), and the Judy Garland Show (1962), and as a dance accompanyist for the film Mary Poppins (1964). Farber died on September 14, 1975, in Los Angeles, CA.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of manuscripts and reproductions of arrangements for The Carol Burnett Show, The Danny Kaye Show, The Dinah Shore Chevy Show, and other productions. Included are manuscript sketches and final copies of vocal, piano, and orchestral scores for transitions, background music, and song and dance numbers. The works of various arrangers are represented. Also included are scripts and air sequence sheets for The Carol Burnett Show.
Organization and Arrangement
This collection has been organized into the following series:
Series 1: Carol Burnett Show
Subseries 1.1: Arrangements
Subseries 1.2: Air sequences and scripts
Series 2: Danny Kaye Show
Series 3: Dinah Shore Show
Series 4: Other shows
Series 5: Unidentified arrangements
Television scripts.; Television music -- Scores.; Television music.; Danny Kaye Show (Television program); Carol Burnett Show; Dinah Shore Chevy Show
- Series 1. Carol Burnett Show, 1963-1975
  Scope and Content
  This series consists of sheet music for the arrangements used in The Carol Burnett Show. Also included are scripts and air sequences for various episodes.
  - Subseries 1.1. Arrangements, 1963-1975
    Sheet music consists largely of manuscripts and reproductions of vocal scores for various song and dance numbers. Contents are largely completed scores, though there are also some sketches and scores with annotations. Includes treatments by Mitzie and Ken Welch, R. Bundock, Max Ehrmann, Coleman Fields, Peter Matz, E.A. Swan, and Fred Werner. Original titles have been maintained and are arranged alphabetically.
    - Ain't Got Nothin But the Blues Medley, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Buda and Pesht, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Carol's Theme, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Charwoman Spot with Puppet (#824), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Cleopatra Finale (#819), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The Desiderata (Vincent Price), 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Down By the Winegar Woiks, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Divertissement Pour Piano, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Dueling Banjos, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Elegance- Xmas, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Elizabethan Rhythm (#704), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Entertain You, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Gershwin Finale, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Harnick and Bock Mini- Musical Finale, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Heist (#602), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - He's the Wizard, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - I Don't Want to Be Nelson, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Irving Berlin Mini- Musical Finale, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - It's a Musical World (#521), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - It's Time to Say So Long, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Scope and Contents note
      Irving Berlin mini-musical finale.
    - Keep It In the Family (#624), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Kiss Me, Bill (#805), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - La Caperucita Roja, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Luck (#805), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Mine (#817), 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Off Broadway Medley (#718), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Oh, To Be a Movie Star, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Punch and Judy Finale, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Shower Song, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Sondheim Medley (#802), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Swan Lake, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - There Was a Little Girl Medley, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Tongue Twisters, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Cleopatra finale, Harnick and Bock mini-musical finale.
    - Warren Medley, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - You're So London, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 1.2. Air sequences and scripts, 1974-1975
    - Production #802- final revision, 1974 August 21 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Production #811- first draft, 1974 November 7 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Production #818- final revision, 1975 January 16 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Production #824- first draft, 1975 March 13 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Production #901- first draft, 1975 July 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Production #902- first draft, 1975 July 10 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Untitled production, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Script likely belongs to episode #902, featuring Sammy Davis Jr. Aired 20 September 1975.
- Series 2. Danny Kaye Show, 1963-1967
  This series consists of sheet music for the arrangements used in The Danny Kaye Show, and largely contains manuscript sketches for vocal, piano, and orchestral scores, though there are also a few reproductions. Includes arrangements by Billy Barnes and Earl Brown. Original titles have been maintained and arranged alphabetically.
  - The Ballad of Red Ridin' Hood, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cake Walk Impressions, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Christmas Fantasy Dance - Old Friends Medley, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Come Dance With Me, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Conductor Sketch, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cute, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Gwen Verdon Dance Production, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Hand Me Down My Walkin Cane, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Haven't We Met, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Hit Parade Medley, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Huckleberry Duck, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - I'm a Brass Band, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - I Must Know (lyrics sheet), undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - I've Got Your Number, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Just an Honest Mistake, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Mutual Admiration Society, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Puttin' On the Ritz, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Suite For Odd Ball Instruments, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Swan Lake, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Table Dance Production, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Thou Swell, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Till Ballet, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Vickie, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Walk It Off, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Work A John, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - You Make Me Feel So Young, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Series 3. Dinah Shore Chevy Show, 1957-1963
  This series consists of sheet music for the arrangements used in The Dinah Shore Chevy Show, and includes manuscripts and reproductions of vocal and piano scores. Includes arrangements by Earl Brown and Harry Zimmerman. Original titles have been maintained and arranged alphabetically.
  - Rehearsal schedule and song list, 1961 June 11 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Al Hirt, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Bewitched (Show #2), 1957 October 27 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bing Crosby, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Bud and Travis Intro, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Can- Can Production Dance, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Dinah Intro No. 1 & 6, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - For Me And My Gal (Show #3), 1957 November 3 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Frank Sinatra, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Guys and Dolls, circa 1961 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - In the Still of the Night, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Let's Go Shopping, circa 1961 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Mad About Him Blues, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Most Beautiful Girl, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Spiritual Medley, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Series 4. Other shows, 1963-1972
  This series contains sheet music for the arrangements used in various other shows. It consists largely of reproductions of completed vocal scores, though a few manuscript sketches are also included.
  Includes arrangements by Peter Jennaro and Vic Shoen.
  - Glen Campbell Goodtime Hour: "I'll Never Fall in Love Again", 1969 March 24 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Judy Garland Show: "West Side Story Medley (Show #17)", 1963 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Rex Allen Show: "Deadwood Stage", undated; Series 5. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Mary Tyler Moore Show: "Ten Cents a Dance", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Mary Tyler Moore Show: "30s Movie Production Number", undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Series 5. Unidentified arrangements, 1955-[circa 1965]
  This series consists of titled but largely undated sheet music works. Affiliation has not been conclusively established for these scores, but they likely belong, at least in part, to the television shows named in previous series. Includes manuscripts and reproductions of vocal scores, instrumental parts, and a few full scores. There is an equal distribution of finished scores and sketches. Original titles have been maintained and grouped alphabetically by letter.
  Includes arrangements by Jerry Bock, Luiz Bonfa, Don Ellis, Ray Evans, Hal Hopper, Jay Livingston, Johnny Mann, Richard Priborsky, Richard Sherman, Robert Sherman, and Paul Weston.
  - A (Box 6, Folder 1)
    African Noel (undated)
    Alfred Hitchcock movie (undated)
    Apache Tack (undated)
  - B (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Barefoot Contessa- Bolero (undated)
    The Berry Tree (undated)
    Brother John (undated)
  - C (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Can- Can Impressions (undated)
    Cherry Pink and Apple Blossom White (undated)
    Chihuahua Choo- Choo (1958)
    Children Board That Train (undated)
    Children's Suite (undated)
    Circus Impressions (undated)
    Coping With Copland. Cope With the Red Pony Dance (Gwen Verdon) (undated)
    Crazy Otto (undated)
  - D (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Dance With My Henry (undated)
    Dancing Pagodas (undated)
    Davy Crockett (undated)
    Days of Wine and Roses (undated)
    Doll Dance (undated)
  - E (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Earth Angel (undated)
  - F (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Fiery Web Tarantella (undated)
    Fiddler on the Roof: "Anatekva" (1964)
    Fiddler on the Roof: "To Life" (undated)
    Fools Rush In (undated)
    Four Leaf Clover (undated)
  - G (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Got Eyes on You (undated)
    Go West, Young Gwen (undated)
  - H (Box 7, Folder 2)
    The Hasegawa General Store (1964)
    How Important Can It Be? (undated)
  - I (Box 7, Folder 3)
    I Can't Stop Loving You (undated)
    I'm All I've Got (Liza Minelli) (undated)
    I'm a Toy (undated)
    Incantation Ballet (undated)
    I Spy Play-on (Bill Cosby) (undated)
    It May Sound Silly (undated)
    It's a Good Day (Big Country Western) (undated)
    It's So Nice to Have a Man Around the House (Lovelady Powell) (undated)
  - J (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Jamaica- House of Flowers (undated)
    Jazz Waltz (undated)
  - K (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Kokomo (1955 January 31)
  - L (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Laura (undated)
    Lawrence of Arabia Dance (undated)
    Le Grand Petit Ballet (undated)
    Lost Letter- Walk on the Wild Side (undated)
  - M (Box 7, Folder 7, Box 8, Folder 1)
    Malaguena (undated)
    Mambo #5 (undated)
    Mambo Jambo (undated)
    Marches (undated)
    Melody of Love (undated)
    Midnight Cowboy (undated)
    More (undated)
    Mt from Tom Jones (undated)
  - N (Box 8, Folder 2)
    No More (undated)
  - O (Box 8, Folder 3)
    One Man Band Routine (undated)
    Open Up Your Heart (undated)
    Opening Jazz Dance (undated)
  - P (Box 8, Folder 4)
    The Pirate (1960)
    Pledging My Love (undated)
    Polka (undated)
    Prop Dance (undated)
  - R (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Rhythm (undated)
    Ridin' On the Moon (undated)
    Rock Around the Clock (undated)
    Rockin' Chair General Store (undated)
    Rock Love (undated)
  - S (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    Scotch- Coming Through the Rye (undated)
    The Seven- Ups (undated)
    Sewing Date (undated)
    Seymour and the Gladiators (undated)
    Shadow of Your Smile (undated)
    She Touched Me (undated)
    Shoes (undated)
    Sincerely (undated)
    Sixteen Tons (undated)
    Slow Movement- String Suite (undated)
    Small Talk (undated)
    Sounds (undated)
    Spellbound- Dance Production (undated)
    Spirit of Summer (undated)
    Stardust Mambo (undated)
    Straw Hat Song (undated)
    Style (undated)
  - T (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
    Tango Impressions (undated)
    Tarantella #2- Pizzica Pizzica Po (undated)
    That's All (undated)
    Theme from Romeo and Juliet (undated)
    Themes from Dr. Zhivago (undated)
    There Goes My Heart (undated)
    Think Pink (undated)
    This Home, Our Home (undated)
    T.V. Waltz Revels (undated)
    Tweedle Dee Dee (undated)
    Two Hearts (undated)
  - U (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Unchained Melody (undated)
  - W (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Walk on the Wild Side (undated)
    Wall Street (undated)
    Whatever Lola Wants (circa 1955)
    When I'm Not Near the Girl I Love (undated)